sampleresume.net 2019-02-08

# Policy | Privacy Policy | Resume-Now

###### Effective Date: May 25, 2018

###### 1\. Scope and Consent

Provider is an online destination that provides resume and cover letter building, career tests, salary information and other products and services for individuals seeking to further their career! We do not guarantee employment for any user of this Site. Nor do we guarantee that any employer will find qualified candidates through this Site. When you use the Site, you are contracting with Provider. If you reside outside of the United States Provider [Bold LLC, City View Plaza II 48 Road 165 Suite 6000 Guaynabo, Puerto Rico 00968] is your data controller. By using the Site, you expressly consent to our collection, use, disclosure, and retention of your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy.

###### 2\. Information We Collect

a) **Registration, Product and Account Information** : You can browse the Site without telling us who you are or revealing any Personal Information (e.g., name, email address, phone number, mobile telephone number, credit card information or physical contact information) about yourself. If you register for an account with us, post a resume, create an email account using our platform, or use some of our products and services (e.g., Site e-mail account(s), Resume Builder, Resume-Check, Resume Guide, Cover Letter Builder, Cover Letter Tips, My Perfect Resume, Resume Review, Resume Writing, Resume Services, Search Jobs) you choose to give us your Personal Information and are not anonymous to us. When you register an account or use certain of our products and services, create a profile, create a resume, search for or purchase products, create an email account on our Site, or otherwise engage with our Site, you can provide certain Personal Information (e.g., username and e-mail address). You can also provide payment information (e.g., credit or debit card information, name and billing address) to purchase products and services. Personal Information is only associated with your account/profile when you sign in as a registered user.

b) **Information to respond to your requests:** You can give us your Personal Information so we can respond to your questions and requests as well as send you newsletters and other communications you request. Details of how you can opt-out of receiving any communications from us are detailed in the section headed Accessing, Reviewing, and Changing Your Personal Information

c) **Social Media Information:** We can offer sign-on services that allow you to use third-party login credentials to access the Site. We also can offer services that allow you to share information with third-party social media websites such as Facebook, Google Plus, Twitter, and others. When you link your account or engage with our Site through third-party social media sites, you understand that you are allowing us to have ongoing access to certain information stored on those social media sites (e.g. your social networking credentials, your public profile, friend list, people you follow or who follow you, pictures, your e-mail address, birthday, work history, education history, interests, current city, religious and political views, website, personal description, and likes, and your friends’ birthdays, education histories, personal descriptions and likes).

We can also receive other information (e.g., content viewed and information about the advertisements within the content you have been shown or have clicked on, etc.) from your interaction with our Site. You agree that we can share your video viewing with or obtain information about your video viewing from analytics providers and advertising partners and third-party partners and social media sites for two years or until you withdraw your consent.

The information we have access to from the third-party social services varies by service and is controlled by your privacy settings on that service and by your consent. Information that can be passed to analytics providers and advertising partners can be via cookies and tracking technologies. Please see our Cookies and Tracking Technologies Policy for information, including your choices in relation to some of these technologies. By associating an account managed by a third-party with your Provider account and authorizing us to have access to this information, you agree that we can collect, use, and store information from these websites in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

d) **Information From Other Sources:** The information we collect can be combined with information from outside public records (e.g., demographic information, navigation information, additional contact information) that we have acquired in accordance with the law.

e) **Mobile Information:** With your consent we can collect additional information from you if you access our Site through a mobile device (e.g. your unique device identifier, device’s operating system, mobile carrier, location or GPS/geo-location, mobile number, your text messages, e-mails or e-mail address, user name, contacts/address book, financial or payment information, web browsing history, photos, your phone’s name, passwords, political interests, sexual orientation, racial or ethnic origin, religious and philosophical beliefs, trade union membership.

f) **Technical Usage Information:** When you visit our Site, we collect usage information sent to us by your computer, mobile, or other access device that tells us how you are using the Site including video-viewing, site views, key stroke data, mouse movement, scrolling, clicks, and typing ("usage information"). We use tracking technologies (including cookies, flash cookies, unique device identifiers, web beacons/GIFs, embedded scripts, e-tags/cache browsers, cross-device tracking) to collect usage information. We can use tracking technologies for a variety of purposes, including:

**Operationally-Necessary**. We can use tracking technologies required for system administration, to prevent fraudulent activity, improve security or allow you to make use of shopping cart functionality. We are not required to obtain your consent to tracking technologies that are operationally necessary.

**Performance-Related**. We can use cookies or other tracking technologies to assess the performance of the online services, including as part of our analytic practices to improve the content offered through the online services. For example, as set forth in detail in our Cookies and Trackings Technology Policy, we use Google Analytics and [Inspectlet](https://www.inspectlet.com/) to perform site analytics.

**Functionality-Related**. We can use tracking technologies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited the Site before or if you are a new visitor and to help us identify the features in which you have the greatest interest.

**Targeting-Related**. We can use tracking technologies to deliver content, including ads, relevant to your interests on our online service and third-party sites based on how you interact with our advertisements or content as well as track the content you access (including video viewing). Further information on this, and your opt-out choices, is below.

We can also collect password information from you when you log in, as well as computer and/or connection information. During some visits we can use software tools to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, time spent on certain pages and page interaction information.

Our goal is to collect and use only that information that we think is required for our legitimate business interests, in order to better understand your interests and improve your experience of using the Site. You consent to our tracking of your video viewing through the Site or Social Media for up to two years or until your consent is withdrawn. To learn more about how we use tracking technologies and cookies, see Section 7 of this Privacy Policy.

g) **Apply Tool Privacy Notice and Information We Collect.** We can automatically collect certain information (including Personal Information) from your device or web browser. We can automatically collect information from location storage associated with your web browser, including your browsing behavior for career searching activity. We can also automatically record your interactions with certain webpages by accessing local storage associated with your web browser. The Apply Tool was made to automatically interact with third party websites, so we can also collect some non-personal data about you when you visit those websites including, clickstream data, operating system being used, the URL of the site you have come from and move to after your visit, data relating to your activities on third party websites (including IP addresses and URLs) via tracking technologies (such as cookies and measurement software), the date and time of your visit and your server's IP address, the geo-location of your device, and the type of payment you use. We collect this information for statistical purposes to find out how our website and the Apply Tool are being used. We can use this information to evaluate and, hopefully, improve your experience. As an example, when you visit a webpage that supports the autofill function, we can record metadata generated by your web browser that identifies one or more autofill fields that you interact with. In this example, we can also access local storage associated with your web browser to determine information (including Personal Information) which can be or has been entered into an autofill field. We use your information to facilitate your completion of job applications across the internet, on our websites and third-party websites and to provide advertising and/or other content that we believe can be of interest to you based upon your browsing behavior on the internet. 

###### 3\. Uses, Retention and Storage

We process your Personal Information for the following purposes and legal bases:

a) **Operate Our Site and Provide You With Our Services:** We use the Personal Information we collect including e-mail account you can create on our platform using Provider mail to (i) respond to your questions and requests; (ii) provide customer service (e.g., to fulfill product and service orders made by you, give you information about your account to resolve disputes, problems with your account/profile or the Site, administer a contest, sweepstakes or promotion, or to provide information to third parties at your request such as potential employers, job matching services or third party websites, or other career related services); (iii) personalize your experience by providing content on the Site, including targeted advertising or job-related advertising, that we believe can be of most interest to you; (iv) improve the Site; (and (v) provide you with a safe, efficient, and customized experience.

b) **Analyze and Aggregate Non-Personal Information:** We use aggregate information about our users and non-Personal Information to analyze Site and user behavior and prepare aggregated reports.

c) **Prevent Fraud and Comply with the law:** We use information from the Site to prevent, detect, and investigate fraud, security breaches, and potentially prohibited or illegal activities, establish, exercise or defend a legal claim, and enforce our Terms of Use. We also use information in response to requests by government or law enforcement authorities conducting an investigation, or in response to complaints where we are under a legal or regulatory obligation to adhere to a complaints handling procedure.

d) **Communicate With You and Third Parties at Your Request:** We use your information to contact you to maintain the Site, your account, or to comply with your stated communication preferences, or to provide other products or services requested by you, as described at the time when we collect the information from you, or to contact you for other purposes authorized by law. If you have chosen to participate in some of our career building Services, the information you share with us can be provided to third parties such as (i) resume editors, (ii) employers or recruiters who can contact you about career opportunities, (iii) employers seeking candidates and/or (iii) other career service providers.

e) **Mobile Data:** When you access the Site on a mobile device, with your consent we can use the information collected for any purpose set forth in this Privacy Policy. For example, we can use this information to provide you with location-based services, such as advertising, search results, and other personalized content. We retain Personal Information for as long as it is necessary to fulfill the purpose(s) for which it was collected, our business purposes and/or to comply with the applicable laws, and your consent to such purpose(s) remains valid after termination of our relationship with you. You consent to our retention of your video viewing tracking data for as long as permissible under applicable law – up to one year after you close your account or otherwise withdraw consent for video tracking.

###### 4\. Disclosure

Information we collect can be shared with:

a) **The Provider Corporate Family and Other Third Parties:** We can share the information we collect about you with the Provider corporate family (our affiliates as well as with third party suppliers. The information can be disclosed (i) to provide joint content and our products and services (e.g., registration, transactions, employment or education opportunities, analytics and customer support); (ii) to help detect and prevent potentially illegal acts, violations of our policies, fraud and/or data security breaches; and (iii) to guide decisions about our Provider or third party’s products, sites, applications, services, tools, and communications. Members of our corporate family will use this information to send you marketing communications and you will have the opportunity to opt-out of e-mail communications.

b) **Service Providers and Other Third Parties:** We can disclose your information to service providers under contract who help with our business operations (such as, but not limited to, fraud investigations, bill collection, payment processing, and site analytics and operations). Also, we share information with our third-party payment processors. With your authorization, we can also share your information with potential employers, career/job-posting websites.

c) **Other Entities with your Consent:** We can share your Personal Information with third parties to whom you explicitly ask us to send your information (such as resume editors, employers, recruiters or job posting third party websites or others about whom you are otherwise explicitly notified and consent to when using a specific service). These third party’s services are governed by their own terms of service and privacy policies as set forth by the third parties that provide them. We do not necessarily endorse nor are we responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for those services. On the Site, you have opportunities to express interest in or register for other products and services. If you do, we will provide information about you to those third parties, or parties working on their behalf, to implement your request.

d) **Legal and Law Enforcement:** Law enforcement, governmental agencies, or authorized third parties, in response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity or any other activity that can expose us, you, or any other Provider user to legal liability. In such events, we will only disclose information relevant and necessary to the investigation or inquiry, such as name, city, state, ZIP code, telephone number, e-mail address, user ID history, IP address, fraud complaints, and anything else we deem relevant to the investigation.

e) **Change of Control – New Owners:** Other business entities, should we plan to merge with or be acquired by that business entity. Should such a combination occur, we will make reasonable efforts to request that the new combined entity follow this Privacy Policy with respect to your Personal Information. If your Personal Information would be used contrary to this policy, we will request that the new owner provide you with prior notice and depending on the circumstances, an opportunity to opt-in to or opt-out of the new use.

f) **Ad Networks:** On the Site, we can work with third parties to serve advertisement, provide us with data collection, reporting, ad response measurement and site analytics and assist with delivery of relevant marketing messages and advertisements. These third parties can view, edit or set their own tracking technologies/cookies. The use of these technologies by these third parties is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by this Privacy Policy. They can also obtain information about other applications that you have downloaded to your mobile device, the mobile websites you visit and other information about you or your device in order to analyze and serve anonymous targeted advertising on the Site and elsewhere. For more information about third party ad servers at our Site and your ability to opt-out of targeted advertising from such third parties, please visit <https://www.aboutads.info/choices/> which provides information about certain companies that we can be using to serve advertising on our Site.

g) **Companies In The Mobile App Industry:** If you access the Site through a mobile device or app, we can also share your information with Carriers, operating systems and platforms.

###### 5\. Your Choices

a) **Opting Out of Promotional Messages:** You can choose not to receive our promotional communications by clicking the "My Account" tab and clicking the "My Settings" and "Preferences" tabs. You can also click the unsubscribe link in the footer of any e-mail or newsletter you receive. You can also e-mail us at [privacy@bold.com](mailto:privacy@bold.com).

b) **Update/Delete or Change Your Resume or Cover Letter:** To change or delete your resumes or cover letters, login to your Provider account and click "Resume" and "Cover Letter" tabs and select edit or delete.

c) **Site Privacy Settings:** Information that you disclose while participating on the Site can be public and subject to redistribution by us and any third-party that reviews your profile or information that you post. You can change preferences for other Provider services as set forth in section 8 or by contacting us as set forth in Section 15. Please be aware that Provider is not responsible for the uses, disclosures or copies of your public postings on or through the Site that you make public and that are downloaded by third parties.

d) **Administrative Messages Cannot Be Turned Off:** As Provider provides an on-line service you cannot opt-out of administrative e-mails (for example e-mails about your transactions or policy changes) for your registered account.

e) **Deletion of Your User Content/Account:** You can request that we delete your account by logging into your account and clicking the "My Settings" and "Overview" tab. You can also e-mail us at [privacy@bold.com](mailto:privacy@bold.com). When you request that your account be deleted your Personal Information, including your resume and profiles will be deleted and no longer available to you or visible to users from Provider Applications but if any of your information, including your Personal Information, was previously accessed by others using Provider Applications, we are unable to delete the information from their systems. When you delete your information on Provider Applications we will retain logs and non-personally identifiable information about you along with an archival copy of your information, which is not accessible by you or third parties on Provider Applications but which might be used by us for recordkeeping and internal purposes, including enforcing this Policy and demographic, reporting and research purposes.

f) **Timing and Third Parties:** We will endeavor to comply with your requests as soon as reasonably possible but please note that changes requested of us are not always effective immediately. Unless required by law, we are not responsible for informing third parties (including without limitation our third party service providers, potential employers, job-posting sites you authorize us to contact on your behalf, or strategic or marketing partners) with whom we have already shared your information of any changes requested pursuant to this section, or for removing information from or causing information to be removed from the databases or records of such entities.

###### 6\. Information You Share on the Site.

If you participate in Provider services (e.g., resume posting, profile creation, Job Alerts) that permit you or Provider on your behalf to post information on third party sites (e.g., websites, bulletin boards, personal urls) and if you post information or content, such as by posting photos, or participating in online forums or communities, when you interact with our Site through social media sites, plug-ins or other applications, depending upon your privacy settings, this information can become public on the Internet. We cannot prevent further use of this information. You can control what data you share through privacy settings available on some social media sites. Please refer to those third party sites’ privacy policies and terms of use to learn more about their privacy practices, which we do not control.

**Other services:** If you use the Site, Provider can create a universal application derived from the information you provide on the Site that will be visible to potential employers who have immediate needs for prospects as well as visitors to the Site. Therefore, your Site Profile can be publicly viewable. You can elect to have your Profile restricted to registered users only by following the instructions on the Site for that particular setting. You agree that employers and Provider will use the contact information you have provided to contact you by e-mail and you understand that this consent is not a condition to having access to the Site or Provider services. 

If you opt-in to our SMS alert service, you acknowledge that message or data charges may apply. If you wish to not continue with the SMS alert service, you may opt-out by replying “STOP” to the SMS text you received or contact our customer service. Please allow 3 to 5 business days to process your request. Provider reserves the right to terminate at its sole discretion the SMS alert service for any reason at any time.

###### 7\. Tracking Technologies (Cookies)

When you visit the Site, we and our business partners can use tracking technologies to enhance your online experience or customize our offerings. A few additional important things you should know about our use of tracking technologies (cookies):

  * We can offer certain features that are available only through the use of tracking technologies.

  * We use both session and persistent tracking technologies. Tracking technologies (e.g., cookies) can either be persistent (i.e., they remain on your computer until you delete them) or temporary (i.e., they last only until you close your browser). You are always free to decline tracking technologies if your browser permits, although doing so can interfere with your use of the Site. Refer to the help section of your browser, browser extensions, or installed applications for instructions on blocking, deleting, or disabling tracking technologies such as cookies.

  * We encode and protect the tracking technologies that Provider sets, so that only we can interpret the information stored in them. You can encounter tracking technologies/cookies from our third party service providers, that we have allowed on our Site that assist us with various aspects of our Site operations and services, such as Google Analytics.

  * You can also encounter tracking technologies from third parties on certain pages of the websites that we do not control and have not authorized. (For example, if you view a web page created by another user, there can be a cookie placed by that web page).

  * We can target and track the videos you view on the Site. You consent to our tracking of your video viewing through the Site or third party social media for up to two years or as permitted by applicable law.

For more information about the use of cookies and similar technology on our Site please review this Privacy Policy and our Tracking Technologies Policy.

###### 8\. Accessing, Reviewing, and Changing Your Personal Information

Registered members can review and change Personal Information at any time by accessing their accounts on the Site (through the My Account and My Settings tabs). You should promptly update your Personal Information if it changes or becomes inaccurate. We can retain some information from closed accounts so that we can comply with law, prevent fraud, assist with investigations, resolve disputes, analyze or troubleshoot programs, enforce our Terms of Use, or take other actions permitted by law. Likewise, if your account or membership is terminated or suspended, we can maintain some information to prevent re-registration. For non-registered members, you can update or request to access your Personal Information by contacting us as set forth in Section 15. We will endeavor to comply with your requests as soon as reasonably possible but please note that changes requested of us are not always effective immediately. Unless required by law, we are not responsible for informing third parties (including without limitation our third party service providers, potential employers, job-posting sites you authorize us to contact on your behalf, or strategic or marketing partners) with whom we have already shared your information of any changes requested pursuant to this section, or for removing information from or causing information to be removed from the databases or records of such entities.

###### 9\. Notice to California Residents

a) California Civil Code Section 1798.83, known as the "Shine The Light" law, permits our customers who are California residents to request and obtain from us a list of what Personal Information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year and the names and addresses of those third parties. Requests can be made only once a year and are free of charge. To make such a request, please contact us at [californiarequest@bold.com](mailto:californiarequest@bold.com). For all requests, you must put the statement "Your California Privacy Rights" in the body of your request, as well as your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. In the body of your request, please provide enough information for us to determine if this applies to you. You need to attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for our response. Please note that we will not accept requests via the telephone, mail, or by facsimile, and we are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or that do not have complete information.

b) California Business & Professions Code Section 22575 (b) provides that California residents are entitled to know how Provider responds to "Do Not Track" browser settings. Provider does not currently take actions to respond to Do Not Track signals because a uniform technological standard has not yet been adopted. We continue to review new technologies and may adopt a standard once one is universally accepted.

###### 10\. Notice to Residents of the European Union

Provider complies with the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR"). As such, Provider affords to all European data subjects their respective data privacy rights to the extent they are applicable including: (i) right to rectify inaccurate data; (ii) right to erasure (deletion of your Personal Information); (iii) right to restrict processing of your Personal Information; (iv) right of data portability; and (v) right to object. You can exercise any of these rights by contacting us at [boldforeigndispute@bold.com](mailto:boldforeigndispute@bold.com) or contact-us. In order to safeguard your Personal Information from unauthorized access, we can ask that you provide sufficient information to identify yourself prior to providing access to your Personal Information.

In certain situations, and subject to applicable law, Provider will not be able or obliged to comply with part or all of your individual requests. Please note that we have the right to refuse and/or charge a monetary fee for requests which are manifestly unfounded or excessive, for example due to their repetitive character. If you have unresolved concerns, you have the right to complain to an EU Supervisory Authority. 

Providing your information to us is optional, but it can impact our ability to offer the Service to you. For example, if you do not provide your complete Personal Information, we will not always be able to respond to your request in a timely manner. 

###### 11\. Third Parties

Our Site can contain links to other third party websites and Provider can provide products and services that share information with third party sites for your job search. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these third party sites so it is important to familiarize yourself with their privacy policies before providing your Personal Information. 

###### 12\. Information Security

We maintain technical, physical, and administrative security measures designed to protect the security of your Personal Information against loss, misuse, unauthorized or accidental access, disclosure, copying, use or alteration. Some of the safeguards we use are firewalls, data encryption, physical access controls to our data centers, information access authorization controls and other measures in accordance with industry standards. However, no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is totally secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

###### 13\. Children's Privacy

The Site is a general audience site and it is not intended for children under the age of 16. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information via our websites, applications, services, or tools from users in this age group.

If you are a minor and want to remove the information you posted to the Site, please contact us via the email or mailing address listed in Section 16 below. Removal of the information you posted does not ensure its complete or comprehensive removal.

###### 14\. Storage and International Transfer

As we operate internationally, and many of our computer systems are currently based globally, for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy your Personal Information can be stored and processed elsewhere by us, our affiliates or an unaffiliated service provider. The data protection and privacy regulations do not always offer the same level of protection as in other parts of the world, such as the European Economic Area (“EEA”). When you create an account/profile or otherwise provide us with Personal Information, you consent to the collection, storage and/or processing of your Personal Information in the United States, Canada and other countries of your Personal Information and tracking technologies/cookies as described in this Privacy Policy. We take appropriate measures to ensure adequate protection of the privacy rights of EEA data subjects with respect to Personal Information that we transfer outside the EEA to a country that is not subject to an adequacy decision by the EU Commission. To obtain a copy of the relevant transfer mechanism or additional information on the transfers, please address these requests to contact-us. 

###### 15\. Notification Regarding Updates.

From time to time, we can choose to update this Privacy Policy. The Privacy Policy posted at any time or from time to time via this Site shall be deemed to be the Privacy Policy then in effect. You agree that we can notify you about material changes in the way we treat Personal Information by placing a notice on the Site. You should check the Site frequently for updates. In addition, we have provided the Privacy Policy Highlights section to offer a summary of the main points of our Full Privacy Policy for your convenience. In the event of a conflict between the Privacy Policy Highlights and the Full Privacy Policy, the Full Privacy Policy will control.

###### 16\. Contact Us

If your questions are not answered online, you can e-mail us at [privacy@bold.com](mailto:privacy@bold.com), or write to us at Auxiliant sarl, 1A, rue Thomas Edison, L-445 Strassen, Luxembourg or BOLD LLC, City View Plaza II, 48 Road 165, Suite 6000, Guaynabo, PR 00968, or using the contact us form on the Site.
